

506, Y2, Medical department, alley 115, Nui Truc, Kim Ma, Ba Dinh District, Ha Noi City, Viet Nam

| 🗊 gg4acrossover | 🛅 viethoangquoc1402

About

Hi, I'm Viet

I'm a senior IOS Developer in mobile development industry with more than 6 years' experience. I have strong IOS skills, so i can apply OOP, functional programming, design pattern to project. I have high technical skills in both hand-coding objective c/swift and ios libraries (Alamofire, AFNetworking, Mansory, etc). I can build difficult layout without using any library. I learn quickly new technologies and I always try to study and update my skills compared to new trend especially in IOS (I had made Flappy Bird in only three days when the first Swift version published). Besides that, I have enthusiasm and responsibility in working. I can work well under pressure. Finally, I adapted Scrum process.

Education

Military Technical Academy

Ha Noi, Viet Nam

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2012 - 2014

4/2017 - 5/2018

Experience _____

VPBank http://www.vpbank.com.vn/ 5/2018 - present

SENIOR MOBILE ENGINEER

- · Review BRD from Business team
- Create api document for Backend team
- Manage out-source team and review code
- Take over mobile banking project by vendor
- Adapt functional progamming to project
- Write model generator tool for iOS, using stencil
- Implement new features, apply clean architecture

VTVCab http://on.vtvcab.vn/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER • One of two people updated VTVCabOn application and made it better

- Create base project and write document
- Rebuild app for VTVCab using swift
- Develope Remote control in mobile for box 4k
- Find solution and make plan for VTVCab mobile project
- Review code and support vendor to develop ONSport application

Seta-international

http://www.seta-international.com/

LEADER MOBILE TEAM

3/2016 - 4/2017

- Create base project for ecommerce application (like sendo) and define architecture using in this application
- · team lead
- Use SignalR for real time function
- Create and assign task to members
- Merge and resolve conflict (git)
- Use jira to manage project
- · Find solutions for tasks

VNEXT

LEADER IOS TEAM

https://vnext.vn/

2014 - 3/2016

• Create training slide and documentation about: Swift

- Create layout and logic for views and view-controller
- Link server and parse data, upload data to server
- Use sqlite to store and manage data
- Display the location and place direction on map
- Research and use library and third party into the project
- Review code and make convention for ios team
- · Publish app to app store
- Maintain project

My start up team

GAME DEVELOPER 2013 - 2014

- Using C++ to create logic and UI for game
- research technologies to use in project
- Create training slide and documentation about: C++, cocos2dx

Skills_

Mobile Development

SWIFT, OBJECTIVE C, C++

Architecture

MCV, MVVM, MVP, VIPER

Revision Control

GIT, SVN

IDE and text editor

VISUAL STUDIO, SUBLIME, XCODE, ITERM

Operating System

UBUNTU & WINDOWS FAMILY & MACOS

Training

SWIFT & C++ & OBJECTIVE C & DESIGN PATTERN

i usually write blog about tech and share my knowledge

Others

WORD, EXCEL, POWERPOINT, VISIO, UML TOOLS

Languages _

Vietnamese

NATIVE SPEAKER

English

Basic

Interests _

Musics

 ${\tt Country, Jazz, Blue, Rock \& Roll, Bolero, etc...\ every songs\ I\ can\ hear\ and\ feel\ good!}$

Sport

BASKETBALL, BILLBOARD

Gaming

SHOOTING, ADVENTURE, STRATEGY

Coding

SWIFT